# **GEORGIOS IS. DETORAKIS, PH.D.**

Eleven years of research experience in scientific laboratories of various disciplines such as computational neuroscience, machine learning, neuromorphic computing, control theory, and robotics. Two years of experience in industrial applications of machine learning, time series analysis, and natural language processing. Strong abilities in combining and bridging different fields such as machine learning, neuroscience, computer science, and mathematics. Strong mathematical skills, especially in linear algebra, dynamical systems, signal processing, control theory, and numerical simulations. Long experience in programming in system and scripting languages.



#### **CONTACT**

- gdetor@protonmail.com
- +1 (949) 2410844
- gdetor.com
- @gdetor
- in Georgios Is. Detorakis
- 0000-0001-5891-1702
- Publication list

#### **SKILLS**

### **Programming Python** C C++Rust **Shell Script** Matlab/Octave HTML/CSS LaTeX Software & Tools **Machine Learning** (e.g., Pytorch, Keras, Sklearn) **NLP** (e.g., spaCy) Visualisation (e.g., Gnuplot, Paraview, Graphviz) Data handling/analysis (e.g., Pandas) **Numerical Libraries** (e.g., FEniCS, LAPACK/BLAS) **HPC Libraries** (e.g., MPI, OpenMP, CUDA) **Neural Simulators** (e.g., Neuron, Brian) Office **Operating Systems** Linux **MacOS** Windows Languages Greek **English** French

### **WORK HISTORY**

# 11/2020 - Now

• Independent Contractor, Irvine, CA, USA Machine Learning Engineer
Time series forecasting and analysis | Computer vision (object detection and tracking)

**6** 08/2019 - 11/2020

♥ adNomus Inc., San Jose, CA, USA Data Science Architect NLP for recommendation systems | Time series (behavioral data) forecasting

**#** 02/2016 - 07/2019

♥ University of California, Irvine, CA, USA Postdoc Researcher

Neuromorphic computing | ML/DL algorithms for neuromorphic computing | Stochastic neural networks

**12/2013 - 12/2015** 

© CentraleSupelec, Gif-sur-Yvette, France Postdoc Researcher
Neuroscience and control theory | Parkinson's disease | Computational modeling

#### **EDUCATION**

**10/2010 - 10/2013** 

Whiversity of Lorraine, Nancy (France)
 Ph.D. in Computer Science
 Cortical plasticity, dynamics neural fields and self-organization

**1** 01/2007 - 04/2009

• University of Crete, Heraklion (Greece) M.Sc. in Brain & Mind Sciences

**1** 09/2002 - 09/2006

University of Crete, Heraklion (Greece)
 B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics
 Mathematical methods and software development track

## **₯** SOFTWARE

GAIM

A C++ library for Genetic Algorithms and Island Models

NSAT

A C/Python simulator for the Neural and Synaptic Array Transceiver (NSAT) neuromorphic framework

NSATcarl

A C++ interface of CARLsim for the NSAT neuromorphic framework

SPySort

A Python package for spike sorting

# **TALKS**

- ➡ Biologically plausible contrastive divergence: Towards an abstract complementary learning system, Hughes Research Laboratory (HRL), Malibu CA (USA), 2017
- Closed-loop deep brain stimulation for Parkinson's disease: A computational study, University of California Irvine, Irvine CA (USA), 2016
- Neural Fields 101, CentraleSupélec, Gif-sur-Yvette (France), 2015
- ★ The perception of touch: A computational approach, Aix Marseille University, Marseille (France), 2014

# **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

Randomized Self-Organizing Map	
N.P. Rougier and G. Is. Detorakis	•
2021  Neural Computation, 33(8)	æ
Stability analysis of a neural field self-organizing map	
G. Detorakis, A. Chaillet, and N.P. Rougier	
## 2020	90
GAIM: A C++ library for Genetic Algorithms and Island Models	
G. Detorakis, and A. Burton	_
2019  The Journal of Open Source Software, 4(44), 1839	æ
Inherent Weight Normalization in Stochastic Neural Networks	
G. Detorakis, S. Dutta, A. Khanna, B. Grisafe, S. Datta, and E. Neftci	
2019 NeurIPS (NIPS) Conference, Vancouver (Canada)	Q <sub>0</sub>
Contrastive Hebbian Learning with Random Feedback Weights	
G. Detorakis, T. Bartley, E. Neftci	
	æ
Neural and Synaptic Array Transceiver: A Brain-Inspired Computing Framework for Embedded Learning	
G. Detorakis, S. Sheik, C. Augustine, S. Paul, B.U. Pedroni, N. Dutt, J. Krichmar, G. Cauwenberghs, E. Neftci	
2018 Frontiers in Neuroscience (Neuromorphic section) 12	٩
	v
Event-Driven Random Back-Propagation: Enabling Neuromorphic Deep Learning Machines	
E. Neftci, S. Paul, C. Augustine, G. Detorakis	
2017 Frontiers in Neuroscience 11, 2017	8
Incremental stability of spatiotemporal delayed dynamics and application to neural fields	
G. Detorakis and A. Chaillet	
2017 © Control and Decision Conference, Melbourne (Australia), 2017	٠,
E 2017 E Control and Decision Control and Pressouring (Neutrality), 2017	v
Event-Driven Random Backpropagation: Enabling Neuromorphic Deep Learning Machines	
E. Neftci, C. Augustine, S. Paul, <b>G. Detorakis</b>	
2017	8
Closed-loop stimulation of a delayed neural fields model of parkinsonian STN-GPe network:	
a theoretical and computational study	
G. Is. Detorakis, A. Chaillet, S. Palfi, and S. Senova	
2015 Frontiers in Neuroscience, 9:237	Q.
Structure of Receptive Fields in a Computational Model of Area 3b of Primary Sensory Cortex	
G. Is. Detorakis and N.P. Rougier	
2014 Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience, 8(76)	æ
A Neural Field Model of the Somatosensory Cortex: Formation, Maintenance and Reorganization	
of Ordered Topographic Maps	
G. Is. Detorakis and N.P. Rougier	
# 2012  ■ PLoS ONE 7(7): e40257	<b>%</b>
Self-Organizing Dynamic Neural Fields	
N.P. Rougier and G. Is. Detorakis	
2011 Advances in Cognitive Neurodynamics III, Hokaido (Japan)	æ